[ Wind Whistling ]
[ Whistling Continues ]
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Chattering ]
- Come on ! - Ha , ha .
[ Speaking Spanish ]
- [ Wind Whistling ] - [ Chattering Continues ]
I forgot where I am .
You 're at the place where the killers need to decide what to do with the crippled girl .
Oh , that 's right . That 's right .
[ Woman Screams ]
Did you hear that ?
- That 's funny . - [ Wind Whistling ]
That 's weird . Those people look like they 're clawing at themselves .
Is that blood ?
[ Dog Barks In Distance ]
[ Woman Screams ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Whimpers ]
Claire , you seeing this ?
Claire .
Claire ? Claire ?
What page was I on ?
What page ?
[ Sirens Blaring ]
- [ Man ] We need an extension over here . - [ Man # 2 ] Pull back !
[ Man # 1 ] Give me , like , another 20 feet .
Don 't touch that . That 's for the drywall guys .
[ Man # 2 ] I told you he wouldn 't do it .
So then the little guy says , " You have a girlfriend named Wendy too ?
Well , I saw your thing and it said ' W.Y. ' "
The big guy says , " No , man .
Mine says ' Welcome to Jamaica . Have a nice day . " '
[ All Laughing ]
Christ . McKenzie fell .
M-Medic . We have a major accident at the south side of the building .
- We 'll need an ambulance . - [ Man On Walkie-talkie ] Copy .
- [ Groaning ] - Jesus .
Give him some room .
[ Thud ]
- [ Man ] Hey ! - [ Woman ] Somebody fell !
- Davis ? - That guy just fell ! Someone fell !
Over at that building !
- [ Thud ] - [ Woman ] Oh , my God !
- [ Man ] Watch it ! - [ Woman ] Oh , my God !
- [ Man # 1 ] Watch it ! - [ Man # 2 ] Get out of there !
[ Woman Screams ]
- [ Man # 3 ] Hey , someone - - Help ! - Look out !
Christ ! Just go ! Look out !
- [ Thud ] - God in heaven .
Look , I don 't know if you guys have heard about this article ...
in the New York Times about honeybees vanishing .
Well , apparently , honeybees are disappearing all over the country .
Tens of millions of them just disappearing .
There 's no bodies , no sign of them . They 're just mysteriously gone .
It 's scary , huh ?
Let 's hear some theories about why this might be happening .
Nothing ? Come on , guys .
- Laura . - [ Girl ] Disease ?
Right . Could be a virus or infection .
But it 's all over the country . It 's a coordinated event in 24 states .
It 's a little tricky .
- Pollution ? - Could be .
I mean , we 're just pumping so much junk into the environment , they 're just keeling over .
But there are no bodies . Keep guessing .
- Dylan . - Global warming .
Temperature goes up a fraction of a degree , makes them disoriented . Maybe .
Jake ?
You don 't have an opinion ?
You 're not interested in what happened to the bees ?
You should be more interested in science , Jake . You know why ?
- Because your face is perfect . - [ Chuckling ]
The problem is your face is perfect at 15 .
Now , if you were interested in science , you would know facts ...
like the human nose and ears grow a fraction of an inch each year .
So a perfect balance of features now might not look so perfect five years from now .
They might look downright whack 10 years from now .
- [ Chuckling ] - Come on , buddy ..
Take an interest in science . What could be a reason the bees have vanished ?
An act of nature and we 'll never fully understand it .
Nice answer , Jake . He 's right .
I mean , science will come up with some reason to put in the books ...
but in the end it 'll be just a theory .
I mean , we will fail to acknowledge ...
that there are forces at work beyond our understanding .
To be a good scientist ...
you must have a respectful awe for the laws of nature .
- Jake ? - How much does the human nose grow each year ?
It 's minuscule , buddy , okay ? Don 't worry about it .
You 're gonna be a heartthrob your whole life . I was just messing with you .
[ Students Chuckling ]
[ Door Opens ]
The Dark Lord . Don 't look into her eyes .
- Whoo ! - [ Giggling ]
Vice Principal . What can we do for you ?
I 'm afraid I have to interrupt you for a moment , Mr. Moore .
- [ Students Oohing ] - Okay , guys , calm down . I 'll be right back .
- [ Chattering ] - [ Boy ] What is that ?
[ Chattering Continues ]
I 've never seen anything like it .
- [ Boy # 2 ] What 's going on ? - I don 't know .
You excused all the teachers ?
The administration makes us teach with a foot of snow on the ground . What is this ?
- [ Chattering ] - Elliot !
All right .
There appears to be an event happening .
Central Park was just hit by what seems to be a terrorist attack .
- [ Woman ] Oh , no . - They 're not clear on the scale yet .
It 's some kind of airborne chemical toxin ...
that 's been released in and around the park .
- [ Murmuring ] - They said to watch for warning signs .
The first stage is confused speech .
The second stage is physical disorientation , loss of direction .
The third stage is fatal .
Central Park ? That 's kind of odd .
I spoke with the head of the schools .
He said we should dismiss the students .
So take your planners home , so we can get back when this is over .
All right ? Let 's do our jobs .
[ Elliot ] You guys still got to work on your science projects for next week .
What are the rules of scientific investigation ?
[ Together ] Identify variables , design the experiment ...
careful observation and measurement , interpretation of experimental data .
Hey , guys ?
Nothing .
[ Man ] Go back to the laughing , please .
My mother just called my cell again . She 's hysterical . Hysterical .
I told her the probability of something happening in Philadelphia is very low .
I mean , nobody 's telling us to leave the city , right ?
So I threw some figures at her .
It 's good to be a math teacher sometimes . People - - People are comforted by percentages .
Didn 't work . She still wants us to get out of the city and come out to her house .
But she said for you and Alma to come .
Yeah . Let me think about that , okay ?
Did you hear about New York ?
Are you okay ? No , I mean are you okay ?
Yeah , me too . Listen , I want to talk about it more .
Julian 's mom offered for all of us to stay with her .
What do you think ?
[ Chattering ]
I 'll bring Jess and Evette and I 'll meet you at the station .
Listen , Julian , if Alma 's acting weird , just be cool , okay ?
- What 's going on ? - She 's acting odd .
Just don 't worry about it , okay ?
- Odd ? - Look , if she 's acting like she 's distant or something .
- What ? - [ Sighs ] I can 't say any more .
- Is she leaving you ? - I didn 't say that . It 's just talk , okay ?
Just relax , please ?
- [ Sighs ] - Hey .
I 'm gonna tell you something you should never tell your best friend .
Why is everybody saying that ?
I saw her on your wedding day .
Again with the wedding . What ?
I walked into a waiting room by mistake and she was crying .
She looked up . I saw her face .
She wasn 't ready to jump in , Elliot . That 's not who she is .
She 's never going to jump in when you need her , man .
[ Man On TV ] So do federal , state and local officials ...
- have a plan in place for this type of catastrophe ? - [ Cell Phone Vibrating ]
- Are they utilizing all the manpower , the money - - - [ TV Off ]
[ Vibrating ]
- Hi . - Are you packed ?
- Yes . - What are they saying ?
They 're evacuating New York City .
Well , our brains come equipped with a self-preservation mechanism ...
to stop us from harmful actions .
This is controlled by a combination ...
of electrochemical signals in the brain .
The blocking of neurotransmitters by certain toxins ...
has been proven to cause hallucinations ...
asphyxiation and paralysis .
This new neurotoxin is basically ...
flipping the preservation switch ...
blocking neurotransmitters in a specific order ...
causing specific self-damaging and catastrophic effects .
- Just how the toxin works - - [ Continues Indistinct ] - It makes you kill yourself .
Just when you thought there couldn 't be any more evil ...
that could be invented .
I 'll be packed in two minutes .
[ Cell Phone Vibrating ]
[ Vibrating Continues ]
[ Man ] Hello ?
- No need to rush . - Sir . Thank you .
Sir , we 'll need to check your suitcase .
Elliot ! Elliot ! [ Whistles ] Elliot !
[ Man On TV ] This just in to the Eyewitness Newsroom , and it 's the latest development .
Autopsies on the first victims confirm ...
the toxin is a natural compound .
The attacks remain confined to the New York metropolitan area .
This is a very , very disturbing story .
[ Man On P.A. ] Track 3 now boarding for Harrisburg .
Hey , Jess . Where 's Evette ?
She was at a shop across town . She got stuck in traffic . She 's gonna take the next train .
- We 'll wait . - No . She wanted us to get on this train with Jess .
- She 'll feel a lot safer . Where 's Alma ? - Restroom .
- Hey , Julian . - [ Man ] Please have your tickets out and ready .
I bought them . [ Chuckles ]
It was like getting one of those Cabbage Patch dolls when they first came out .
- What a madhouse . How are you ? - Good . You ?
Good .
- Okay . Good . Why don 't we - - - I 'm really glad you chose to come .
Thanks . Um , Elliot , can I talk to you for a second ?
Yeah .
[ Man ] Please show me your tickets , ladies and gentlemen .
- Have your tickets out , please . - You told him about our fight ?
No .
- Why did he say that ? - He guessed .
I love you , Elliot , but I don 't like to put my feelings out there for everyone to see .
I 'm not that type of person .
Elliot , these are our problems .
- [ Groans ] - I am upset .
I 'm gonna sit alone and cool off . By the time we get there , I 'll be fine .
- Is that okay ? - Fine .
I 'm gonna get on the train . We 're not gonna get to sit together anyways .
Okay .
- Hey , babe . - Hi , Aunt Alma .
- How you doing ? - Hanging in there .
Me too .
- What 's wrong with you ? - What ?
You 're wrong about her . She just needs time to figure it out .
- Come on , don 't get all sensitive . - Just give her a chance .
- Okay , fine . If you don 't want my help - - - I don 't want your help . Duh .
- Okay . I heard it . - Jess , could you ask your dad for my ticket , please ?
Thank you . See you on the train , Jess .
[ Man On P.A. ] Track 3 now boarding all ticketed passengers .
Here we go .
Will Mom meet us at Grandma 's ?
Mommy 's gonna get on the next train .
You know how she 's always late . [ Chuckles ]
[ Chattering ]
- I 'm serious . Come on . Come on . - Mom - -
I know . I know you don 't want to .
[ Wind Whistling ]
- Chilly , isn 't it today , Sal ? - Maybe a little .
[ Barking ]
[ Whimpers , Barking ]
[ Gunshot ]
- [ Gunshot ] - [ Horn Blowing ]
Hey , it 's me . I 'm on a train . I just want to say something , okay ?
You 've got to stop calling me . You 're acting like the Fatal Attraction guy here .
I feel like I 'm gonna take a shower and see your silhouette on the shower curtain .
We ate tiramisu together . That is it .
I told you that would be it . You have got to chill out .
What ?
When ? In Philadelphia ?
- [ Chattering ] - [ Man ] Well , I don 't know . What did you hear ?
[ Chattering ]
- What 's the news ? - Apparently Philadelphia was just attacked .
- Oh , my God . Evette . - Call Mommy ! Call Mommy !
Honey ! Honey , yeah , where are you ?
What ? What ? I-I can 't hear you .
I said I can 't hear you ! Text me .
Text me . I can 't hear you !
They think it started in Rittenhouse Square Park .
Another park ?
- Hey , she got on a bus going to New Jersey . - I want to talk to her .
I know , baby . She got out . She 's headed to the town of Princeton .
I want to talk to her .
- ... get themselves out . - Hello ?
[ Chattering Continues ]
- Do you have a phone ? - No , no . I 'm sorry . I don 't .
- You okay ? - They say Boston got hit too .
- Where 'd you hear that ? - A friend from work . What about Evette ?
Oh , God . She made it out on a bus .
What the hell is going on , Elliot ?
I honestly don 't know .
[ Brakes Screeching ]
[ Alma ] Now what ?
We just stopped . I don 't know .
They 're not telling us anything .
- Sir ? - Train service has been discontinued .
This will be the last stop for all passengers .
Well , hey .
What do you mean ? Where are we ?
Filbert , Pennsylvania .
Filbert ? Does anybody know where that is ?
Why are you giving me one useless piece of information at a time ? What 's going on ?
Hey , why would you just stop ? You can 't just leave us here .
- Sir , we lost contact . - With whom ?
Everyone .
[ Whispering ] I 'm scared . I don 't like it here .
- I want Mom . - Don 't be silly . We 're safe here . Okay ?
I 'm sorry . She whispers to us when she gets scared .
We 're so much the same , Jess . I don 't like to show my emotions either .
- She 's shivering . - I know . She 's never right without her mom .
- It 's okay . - [ Elliot ] They 're not saying anything .
We 're stuck here .
Is Jess okay ?
She 's not talking .
We 're in a small town , Jess . Nothing will happen to us here .
- ¶ ¶ [ Jukebox : Country ] - [ Chattering ]
[ Julian ] Don 't know what you want ?
Just have the grilled cheese , with milk . Come over here .
No . You know what ? Stay here , all right ? You can see me from over there .
What ? All right , you want to come with me ? You can come and wait in line ?
Bro , I got it . Go get the milk .
All right , yeah . Okay .
You know that everyone gives off energy , right ?
It 's scientifically proven .
They got these cameras that can record what color you are when you 're feeling different things .
People that are angry give off a different color than people that are sad .
See this ring ? This ring can supposedly tell you what you 're feeling .
Let 's see what you 're feeling right now .
Oh , yellow . That 's cool . That means you 're about to laugh .
I 'm not making it up . That 's what yellow means .
You must be about to laugh or something . It 's probably just about to come out .
We 'll wait .
We got all day .
[ Growls ]
Oh , my God . There it is .
Cool . That ring really works . That 's amazing .
[ Woman ] Oh , my God . Oh , my God . Look at this .
My sister sent it to me . It was taken an hour ago at the Philadelphia Zoo .
[ Woman On Video ] Oh , I think he 's gonna feed them .
[ Roaring ]
- [ People Screaming ] - [ Lion Roaring ]
Mother of God . What kind of terrorists are these ?
They 're not sure it 's terrorists now .
[ Man On TV ] Moments ago , in an official statement ...
the government moved away from its initial position ...
that this was a terrorist attack .
Authorities are now feeling , by the sheer number of incidents being reported ...
that a terrorist group being responsible is becoming less and less likely .
The event appears to be limited to the Northeast ...
where smaller and smaller towns are being attacked .
- Where are we ? - The affected area now includes most of New England ...
from Massachusetts to Maryland .
- We 're dead center . - [ Murmuring ]
Everything okay ?
- Smaller towns - - - [ Loud Click ]
- [ Brief Electrical Hum ] - [ Gasping ]
If we stay here , we are gonna die here .
[ Man , Indistinct ]
Whatever this is ...
it looks like it 's not occurring about 90 miles from here .
- [ Man ] Let 's go . - [ Chattering ]
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Man ] ... go by car ? Can anyone give us a ride ?
Hey !
- [ Bell Tinkles ] - [ Door Shuts ]
Excuse me , sir ? Sir , can we get a ride , please ?
We don 't have any transportation . We 're stuck here .
Did you hear what I said ? We don 't have any transportation .
We have a little girl with us . Please . Sir ?
- [ Woman ] Drive . Just roll up the window . - Sir !
You 're not just gonna -
[ Engine Starts ] - Can you believe how crappy people are ?
[ Tires Squealing ]
There 's a car .
Um , hi . I , uh - - I run a plant nursery up the street .
We 're , uh , picking up a few things from home ...
then heading ... wherever this isn 't happening .
We-We have room .
- We have two others . - [ Woman ] That 's okay .
Julian !
[ Alma ] Is Julian okay ?
[ Elliot ] We got a ride . He can fit all of us .
Elliot , I can 't get Evette on the phone or e-mail or nothing .
- How long ? - It 's been about two hours .
She was on that bus headed to Princeton .
There 's a car over there headed to pick up friends and family .
- They said they could squeeze one more . - [ Horn Honks ]
Gotta go .
Look . Think real carefully about this .
She was looking for a birthday present for Jess . Some kind of dollhouse .
That 's why she wasn 't with us .
Look , I 'm just gonna go get her , and I 'm gonna bring her back , and I 'm gonna find you guys .
I just - - I need - - I need you to take Jess , okay ?
She 's gonna be a lot safer with you .
Don 't do this to me .
I 'm doing my best here not to fall down .
I 'm sure the probability of Princeton not being hit is good .
Yeah . You want me to throw some figures and percentages at you so we both feel better ?
- Please . - All right .
Sixty-two percent chance - -
Sixty-two percent chance it hasn 't even been hit .
- Well , you go get her , Jules , okay ? - Of course , man .
This is all some weird event , that 's all . We 're all gonna be fine .
- I 'm gonna find you guys real soon . - [ Horn Honks ]
- I have to go . - I got her , Julian .
Don 't take my daughter 's hand unless you mean it .
[ Softly ] Okay .
I 'm gonna go get Mommy .
Hold our picture .
Okay .
Take a look around . We 'll be ready in a jiffy .
¶ ¶ [ Classical On Speaker ]
We 're packing hot dogs for the road .
You know , hot dogs get a bad rap .
They got a cool shape . They got protein .
You like hot dogs , right ?
By the way - -
I think I know what 's causing this .
- You do ? - It 's the plants .
They can release chemicals .
- You like hot dogs , don 't you ? - [ Mouths Word ]
Okay , babies , we are gonna be going ...
but we will be back soon , okay ?
Oh . Plants react to human stimulus . They proved it in tests .
[ Mouthing Words ]
Did you get the mustard ?
[ Screaming ]
- Don 't look outside . - [ Screaming Continues ]
Stop it ! Stop it ! Just look at me ! Just keep looking at me !
[ Whimpering ]
Close the vents .
I 'm gonna give you a math riddle , okay ?
- And you 're gonna tell me the answer . - What ?
How much - - How much would you have ...
if l said I would pay you a penny on the first day ...
and then two pennies on the second , and then four pennies on the third day ...
and I just kept doubling it and I did this for a month ?
How much money would you have at the end of the month ?
[ Whimpering ]
- Ten dollars . - No . Higher , higher , higher .
Just-Just keep looking at me . Just keep looking at me .
- Twenty dollars ? - No , keep going . Keep going .
[ Wind Whistling ]
Thirty . It 's 30 . It 's $ 30 .
[ Whistling Continues ]
Want me to tell you the answer ?
It 's over $ 10 million .
You 'd have over $ 10 million at the end of the month .
Do you want to hear another one ?
[ Wind Whistling ]
[ Dog Barking In Distance ]
[ Man On Radio ] Water contamination has surfaced ...
as one of the many theories being taken seriously ...
as to the cause of the events in the Northeast . [ Radio Off ]
We have to go through this little community of homes .
A small town called Holcomb . Then we hit the highway .
From there we 're 30 miles from the state line .
[ Sighs ] Okay .
Are those dead animals up ahead ?
- Stop the car . - [ Tires Screeching ]
- You don 't think it 's - - - I don 't know .
You got binoculars in the back from when you were spying on our neighbors .
- Can I have the map ? - Elliot .
Don 't cause a panic , okay ? Jess can hear you .
It 's bodies , isn 't it ? I knew it would be bodies . How could it not be bodies ?
Please , give me the map .
We have to turn around . There 's a right turn about a quarter of a mile back .
We 're just gonna take a different route , honey , okay ?
Oh , it 's the army . We 're safe .
[ Horn Honks ]
My name is Private Auster .
I 'm stationed at West Dover Military Base , about 10 - - 10 miles back .
I think they 've been affected by whatever 's happening .
I lost communication with them .
When I approached the base , I saw military personnel ...
in the barbed wire - - in the fence - -
so I suggest no one take that road .
This town about eight miles behind us - -
There were bodies on the road into town .
Cheese and crackers .
Well , that still leaves us two directions .
[ Vehicle Approaching ]
Just stop ! Stop the vehicle !
- [ Man ] What 's going on ? - [ Auster ] Is everyone all right ?
- We have no communication . - We don 't have a cell phone .
- [ Woman ] I 'll talk to them . - You see anything out of the ordinary on the road ?
Hello ! Please stop !
- [ Tires Screeching ] - Excuse me .
[ Sighs ]
- Who 's Joey ? - Oh , it 's no one .
- Any luck ? - I can 't get Julian on his cell phone .
I 'm sure he 'll be all right . They 'll be okay .
[ Auster ] Has any one seen any other people on the roads ?
- Walking or - - - Maybe he 's onto something .
- What are you talking about ? - I don 't know .
Why did it start in parks ?
It 's the same story . About eight , nine miles back - -
They say there 's a bus in a lake .
F-Five miles back , there were dozens of bodies .
Okay .
Nobody 's going anywhere .
We 're gonna stay right here for a while .
There 's a woman talking to her daughter .
She 's talking to her daughter in Princeton .
- Isn 't that where your friend went ? - Come on .
It 's okay . Honey - - Honey , it 's okay .
You - - She 's so scared .
You just - - You just stay in that room .
You don 't open the door for nothing .
Just keep watching out the window with the tree , baby .
- Someone will come and get you soon . - Tell her - -
Tell her not to go near the window with the tree . Just tell her .
Baby , don 't go near the window with the tree .
Ask her if Princeton 's been affected .
Honey , someone wants to know if-if-if Princeton 's had any problems .
She says everyone 's dead outside .
You just stay in your room . You - -
[ Sobs ] Honey ?
Honey , you 're talking funny . What 's wrong with you ?
- What do you mean ? Everyone 's dead ? - What ?
Stace - - Stacey , you 're scaring me .
I-I-I don 't understand what you 're saying .
What , baby ? I - - She 's just not making any sense .
[ Girl ] Calculus .
I see ... in calculus .
- Calculus . - Stacey .
- Calculus . - Stacey !
- [ Footsteps Running ] - [ Loud Whine ]
Stacey Ann ! No ! Oh , my God !
- I hear wind from outside . - Oh , no , no , no , no , no , no , no , no .
Stacey . Stacey . Stacey . [ Sobbing ]
Oh , no .
- Oh , no ! - She 'll be okay .
[ Woman ] ... her daughter in Princeton .
[ Sobbing ] Oh , damn . Oh , no .
[ Woman ] I don 't know how old she is , but this is her mother .
[ Man ] I don 't think she has anything goin ' on .
We 're gonna go back to the car , okay , Jess ?
[ Auster ] If we went down that road , where would that take us ?
[ Exhales ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Sniffles ]
Oh . Come here . Come here .
[ Sobbing ]
[ Sobbing Continues ]
[ Exhales ]
[ Man ] I just walked down a quarter mile . It was clean .
I can 't tell you what 's after that , but it was clean .
No bodies , no nothing . A quarter mile .
- [ Man # 2 ] That 's not enough . - It 's better than goin ' back - -
[ Man # 2 ] That 'll give us a battle plan .
Everybody will make a clean break .
Elliot 's resilient , isn 't he ?
[ Alma ] Yeah . He never gives up .
You know , plants have the ability to target specific threats .
Tobacco plants , when attacked by heliothis caterpillars ...
will send out a chemical , attracting wasps to kill just those caterpillars .
We don 't know how plants attain these abilities .
They-They just evolve very rapidly .
Which species do you think is doing it , if you think it 's true ?
Plants have the ability to communicate with other species of plants .
Trees can communicate with bushes , bushes with grass and everything in between .
The radio says these attacks started happening in the cities ...
- then went to the towns , and now the roads . - That 's right .
[ Elliot ] Whatever is happening is happening to smaller and smaller populations .
So we shouldn 't be on the roads then .
The terrorists , or whatever , could be watching the roads .
I don 't have any reason to disagree right now .
We 're in the area of attack .
If you can 't find a way through the area of attack ...
we are told to find a safe zone within the area being attacked .
They 're attacking populations .
We need to go where there aren 't that many people - -
Where people don 't travel .
Now , this is Mr. Collins .
He 's a Realtor that works in this area .
If we go west , we 'll hit a county called Arundell .
It 's not on that map .
It would only be on local maps .
Dirt roads . Hardly anybody lives out there .
There 's no significant population there . That 's our safe zone .
We wait it out there till it 's over . Is everyone in agreement ?
- [ Chattering ] - [ Auster ] We should go into two groups .
Those that are ready to go right now ...
and those that need to get things from their cars .
We need to stay in groups .
Stay together !
[ Chattering ]
- We 'll go soon , honey . We 'll go soon . - Mmm . Mmm .
[ Elliot ] Maybe we should have waited for the rest of them .
Stayed in a big group like the private said .
Your phone 's out too ?
What 's wrong ?
Okay , I was gonna tell you . Okay ?
There was this guy . Joey . His name is Joey .
He 's at work . We went out , and we had dessert .
I went out and I had dessert with him ...
when I told you I worked late , and I didn 't work late .
And I 'm feeling really guilty . In case we 're gonna die , I just wanted you to know that .
You lied to me ?
- [ Man ] How much further is it now ? - [ Man # 2 ] How you doing ?
[ Wind Whistling ]
- [ Man ] We need to keep going forward . - [ Man # 2 ] Who made you boss ?
[ Man # 1 ] If y 'all follow him , y 'all gonna die . If you follow me , you 're gonna live .
- [ Man , Indistinct ] - [ Man ] I 'm in charge of this group .
- Ain 't nobody else in charge of this group . - [ Woman Screams ]
My firearm is my friend !
It will not leave my side !
Private Auster ?
My firearm is my friend .
[ Wind Whistling ]
- [ Gunshot ] - [ People Gasp ]
Jesus .
- [ Gunshot ] - [ Gasping ]
- Oh , no . - What " Oh , no " ?
- [ Gunshot ] - [ Woman Screams ]
Is it the toxin ?
The toxin is affecting them ?
[ Woman ] Are those people killing themselves ?
[ Man ] You were with the private . What do we do ?
- We need to do something . - Just let me think .
- [ Gunshot ] - They 're dying .
- I need a second . - They released it ? We 're not near the roads .
We can 't just stand here as uninvolved observers .
I need a second , okay ? Just give me a second .
We 're not gonna be one of those assholes on the news ...
who watches a crime happen and not do something .
- We 're not assholes . - Just a second !
- There were children in that group . - Please tell us what to do .
- I need a second , okay ? - [ Gunshot ]
Why can 't anybody give me a goddamn second ?
All right , be scientific , douche bag .
- Identify the variables . That 's the two groups . - [ Gunshot ]
Design an experiment . That 's where we begin .
- Careful observation and measurement . - [ Gunshot ]
- That 's what I 'm trying to do . Interpret the experimental data . - [ Woman Whimpering ]
- Interpret . - [ Gunshot ]
What if it is the plants ?
Their group was larger than ours .
This thing has been escalating all day .
Smaller and smaller populations have been setting this off .
They react to human stimulus .
Maybe people are setting off the plants .
What are you saying ? That guy was crazy . We have to save them .
They 're already dead .
What if they 're targeting us as threats ?
- This part of the field may not have been set off . - [ Gunshot ]
Something in this field could be releasing the chemical into the air ...
when there 's too many of us together .
Let 's just stay ahead of the wind .
[ Rumbling ]
[ Wind Whistling ]
Let 's just break up into groups .
[ Elliot ] Come on , come on !
- This way ! Follow me ! - [ Whistling Grows Louder ]
[ Woman ] I 'm here . Right here . Keep going .
[ Continues , Indistinct ]
[ Indistinct ]
Come on . Come on .
Here it comes .
Don 't you let go of my hand .
[ Panting ]
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Whistling , Howling Eases ]
Nothing happened .
It was the size of the groups , I think .
Could this really be happening ?
What are your names ?
- Jared . - Josh .
Wait , wait .
[ Door Alarm Bell Dinging , Faint ]
I 'm gonna go see if that truck has a map .
You guys wait here .
[ Dinging Continues ]
[ Woman On Radio ] Why aren 't they looking into nuclear power plants ?
There are 15 or more in the Northeast alone ...
more than anywhere else in the United States .
There 's probably been some leak or something .
- It 's probably poisoning the air . - [ Stops ]
[ Dinging Continues ]
There 's a house over there ! Come on !
It could have been some terrorist booby trap .
Someone stepped on it out in the field .
- Yeah , in a field in " Bumbletown , Pennsylvania . " - I don 't know .
Look . A toxin dissipates quickly in the air .
They 're only potent in a certain density .
The source had to be close to that field , if not in the field .
Here 's one .
Plants have a chemistry to do this .
They release cotransporters into the air .
You think it could be plants ?
I don 't know .
But if it is , and people are setting it off in groups ...
we need to go to the least populated place we can to be safe .
We can 't walk to the borders where this is not happening . It 's too far .
Whatever it is - - terrorists , a nuclear leak , plants - -
it 's probably safe to get away from people right now .
That must be Arundell . It 's 10 miles from here .
Okay , this place must have a bathroom .
- I 'm gonna take Jess , and we can leave . - Hurry .
[ Footsteps Recede ]
[ Rustling ]
Hello ?
My name is Elliot Moore .
I 'm just going to talk in a very positive manner ...
giving off good vibes .
We 're just here to use the bathroom .
Then we 're just gonna leave .
I hope that 's okay .
Plastic .
I 'm talking to a plastic plant .
I 'm still doing it .
- ¶ ¶ [ Bland Pop Playing ] - [ Elliot ] You guys ready to leave ?
These people must have left in a hurry .
I mean , leaving the front door unlocked ?
Hey , everything 's fake .
[ Laughs ]
Why is this happening ?
[ Elliot ] I don 't know for sure , Josh .
But I read this article about the coast of Australia .
It said they found large quantities of a primordial bacteria .
It hadn 't been around for billions of years .
It just appeared in the water .
It 's toxic to humans . Fishermen who come in contact with it are dying .
It feels kind of similar to that , with the bees disappearing ?
I mean , I don 't know . It feels like a pattern .
The nature of events like the one in Australia ...
is that they crest and then stop .
We just have to be alive when it 's over .
- I don 't believe it 's nature . - It may not be .
It could be some other explanation . I don 't know .
Let 's go .
[ Josh ] There are people coming .
[ Elliot ] We can 't stay here . It 's close to the roads .
More and more people will come here .
There 's two groups coming together .
There 's too many of them together .
Run . Run .
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Panting ]
- [ Jared ] Is she your kid ? - No .
- You got kids ? - No .
- How come ? You got a problem ? - No .
- She wanted to wait . - Really ? For what ?
For me to grow - - Why are we talking about this ?
Oh , sweet . I used to love those . Could I see it ?
You need to take , uh , personal responsibility ...
for yourself in a relationship .
- That 'll make a difference . - Okay . Thank you .
- Yeah , man . - Hey , that 's not a toy . It 's got meaning to me .
[ Alma ] Elliot ! Look .
Come on .
Oh , wow .
[ Static On Radio ]
[ Man , Breaking Up ] ... an emergency broadcast .
All those who are still inside the affected area of the Northeast ...
are asked to proceed to the police borders ...
- west of your state . [ Static ] - Come on .
- Come on . - This is an emergency broadcast .
- ... inside the affected area - - - [ Exhales ]
[ Wind Whistling ]
Jess needs a 10-minute rest and some food .
Are you sure ? We should keep going .
I know , but she 's only eight .
What ?
If we 're gonna die , I want you to know something .
I was in a pharmacy a while ago .
There was a really good-looking pharmacist behind the counter .
Really good-looking . I went up and I asked where the cough syrup was .
I didn 't even have a cough ...
and I almost bought it .
I 'm talking about a completely superfluous bottle of cough syrup .
That 's , like , six bucks .
Are you joking ?
[ Whispering ] Thank you .
[ Doorknob Rattles ]
[ Creaking ]
[ Creaking Continues ]
Maybe that 's not a good idea .
I told her just for a minute .
[ Creaking ]
- Mr. Moore , I think I can open this door . - Wait .
We 're a gang now ? We 're gonna take whatever we want ?
- Come on , guys . - Listen , nobody 's home .
We 're just gonna get some food for Jess .
Yeah , and it looks like nobody 's lived here for a long time anyway .
I mean , it 's all boarded up .
[ Elliot ] Maybe we could leave some money .
What kind of tree is this ?
I think it 's a maple .
- Not so high . - [ Creaking Continues ]
Okay , Josh , open the door .
Wait !
I see something . There 's somebody in there .
- You sure ? - Yeah . I saw him move .
I see him .
Let 's stop .
Is there anyway we could get some food ?
We have a little girl . We just wanna get her some food .
[ Man ] You best leave now . You ain 't gonna bring that poison gas in here with you .
Sir , it 's not poison gas . There 's none out here .
- They said to stay inside . - [ Elliot ] We 're fine right now .
Nothing 's happened out here yet .
I mean , you could see that . Just listen to our voices .
We 're perfectly normal .
¶ Oh , blackwater Keep on rolling ¶
¶ Mississippi moon won 't you keep on shining on me ¶ ¶
See ? We 're normal .
[ Man ] You ain 't from around here . You 'd best leave now .
Okay . It 's not worth it .
- Open the door , bitch ! - Hey , Josh , don 't do that .
- He didn 't mean that . - There 's more than one in there .
- Jess ! Jess , come here . - Stop it , Jess .
Listen , we just want some food for a little girl , you pussies !
- [ Alma ] Jess , come here . - Josh , stop it .
[ Man ] Best not let that gas in here .
Sir , the air is fine out here right now . You don 't need to worry .
You might be with the terrorists .
I don 't think it 's terrorists , sir .
- Josh , stop it ! - They 're being crazy , Mr. Moore .
- Show your faces ! - Let the gas in - -
No !
Jared !
[ Jared Thuds On Ground ]
[ Panting ]
We 're gonna get out of this nightmare .
[ Jess Sobbing ]
- [ Alma ] Elliot . - [ Sobbing ]
We have to go . We have to protect Jess .
Okay ?
[ Man ] You 've got to three to get off our porch .
[ Crying ]
Come here . Come here .
No new people have crossed over the border for a few hours .
It appears those residents that are still ...
in the affected area of the Northeast are trying to wait it out .
We have Professor Kendal Wallace of Carnegie Mellon , a statistician , here with us .
Professor , what can you tell us ?
Calculating by the rise in intensity ...
of reports of incidents within the affected area ...
one can guess at a crude timetable .
Uh , one can see the incident is rising in sensitivity .
It would seem fewer and fewer people can provoke the attacks .
Uh , the event should be at its most sensitive tomorrow morning .
Typically , these type of slopes drop precipitously after cresting ...
meaning it could end suddenly at any moment .
Of course , these are only probabilities .
There are some quiet rumblings that the government ...
may be involved in the tragic events playing out in the Northeast .
Now , these rumors have been fueled ...
by the statements of a confidential informant ...
who claims that the C.I.A. has facilities in the Northeast ...
where they are testing drugs with some similar psychotropic properties ...
as a defense against chemical weapons .
C.I.A. and White House officials have declined to respond to these accusations .
Perimeters have been set up all along the East Coast ...
from Maryland all the way to Massachusetts .
This house has no power going to it .
Nobody 's driven on this driveway for a long time , either .
Let me go . You guys stay right here .
[ Creaking ]
[ Creaking Continues ]
[ Bell Clangs ]
[ Woman ] That 's for Clement .
He 's a retriever .
You lost ?
You must be .
There ain 't nothing around here for miles .
Why are you eyeing my lemon drink ?
I suppose the kind thing for me to do is to offer you supper .
[ Footsteps ]
I ain 't gonna ask you again .
[ Clears Throat ] I hope the meal was sufficient .
I wasn 't expecting guests .
This is a beautiful place .
There 's a springhouse in the back .
They used to hide people from slave chasers back there .
It has a speaking tube ...
running under the ground to the main house .
You can hear each other like you were in the same room .
So what 's with you two ?
Who 's chasing who ?
- I 'm sorry ? - [ Chuckles ]
Ain 't no time two people staring at each other ...
standing still , love in both their eyes ...
at the same time , equal . [ Chuckles ]
Truth is , someone is chasing someone .
That 's the way we 's built .
[ Chuckles ] So who 's chasing ?
[ Woman Chuckles ] I knew that . I knew that .
Don 't touch things that aren 't yours .
- Do you have a radio , Mrs. Jones ? - No .
I got enough to fill my time right here .
I mend my own things .
I grow my own food .
Although I ain 't got the touch .
Gardens don 't grow the way they should . Never have .
How do you stay in contact with others ?
I don 't .
How would you know if something were to happen , like a world event ?
Mrs. Jones , um ...
something 's happened along the East Coast .
Whatever it is that you think is so important that you need to tell me , don 't .
Just keep it to yourself .
The world don 't care about me .
I don 't care about it .
Suppose I have to let you spend the night .
Guest room 's up on the left .
Mind the steps .
[ Wind Rustling Leaves ]
[ Whispering ] I 'm scared , Elliot .
[ Whispering ] It 's okay .
I 'm sorry about everything . That Joey thing . I was being stupid .
You 've been great taking care of Jess .
I don 't like this woman .
There 's something " Exorcist-y " about her .
How could she hit Jess like that ?
We need to stay in this house .
You want me to protect you , this is how we have to do it .
Let 's just deal with her .
[ Floorboards Creaking ]
I hear you whispering .
- Planning on stealing something ? - No , ma 'am , we 're not .
Plan on murdering me in my sleep ?
What ? No .
[ Alma , Jess Chattering , Laughing ]
[ Knocking ]
Mrs. Jones ?
Crazy lady .
You trying to steal my things ?
No . No , Mrs. Jones , I actually wanted to talk with you .
You all are gonna leave right now .
Ma 'am , you don 't understand .
There 's something happening in a few states .
- In this region it 's not safe . - Leave now !
[ Door Slams ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Mrs. Jones ] The Lord is my shepherd .
The Lord is my shepherd .
Mrs. Jones , could we talk calmly for a second ?
Please hear me out .
See , I 'm a teacher .
[ Wind Whistling ]
Mrs. Jones ?
Oh , my God .
Alma , shut the windows and the doors !
Alma ?
[ Panting ]
[ Footsteps ]
[ Footsteps Continue ]
[ Pounding ]
[ Footsteps ]
- [ Glass Shatters ] - [ Wind Howling ]
[ Panting ]
[ Alma , Jess Laughing , Faint ]
- Alma ? - [ Alma Speaking , Faint ]
Jess ?
[ Alma , Jess Laughing ]
[ Alma ] Hi , froggy .
- Hi , frog . - [ Jess Laughs ]
- [ Alma , Indistinct ] - [ Laughs ]
[ Alma , Indistinct ]
[ Alma ] Over here . Over here . Wait . Up !
How old do you think he is ? Is he a baby ?
I think he 's a baby . [ Laughs ]
He 's so tiny . I didn 't know frogs could be that tiny .
- He got water on my shoe . - [ Laughs ]
Isn 't this a cool house ?
If we had this house , we could make it look so pretty .
[ Alma Laughs ]
Wait . Get him again . Get him again .
- Hey , froggy . - [ Elliot ] Alma ?
Good morning , Elliot . Sounds like you 're right here .
[ Elliot On Speaking Tube ] Close the windows and the doors , Alma .
Why ?
Mrs. Jones just died .
Close the windows .
Close the door , Jess .
[ Wind Whistling ]
- Is everything closed ? - [ Alma ] Yes .
I 'm sorry , Alma .
What 's going on , Elliot ?
It 's happening here .
It could be the grass and the trees are doing this now .
She was alone when it happened .
Seems like they might have gotten more sensitive .
It 's too dangerous to go outside , isn 't it ?
Yes .
This is the end , isn 't it ?
I wish you were here .
Me too .
[ Elliot ] You remember our first date ?
- [ Laughs ] - You were so quiet .
You bought me the mood ring .
It turned purple when you wore it .
[ Laughs ] Then you said , " That means you 're in love . "
It got you to talk , didn 't it ?
Then-Then we checked the little paper chart ...
and it turned out that purple meant I was horny .
[ Laughs ] You loved that .
I had no idea .
Yours was blue .
- Peaceful , right ? - Right .
What color was love ?
I don 't remember .
Me neither .
Elliot ?
Yeah ?
I was just making sure you 're there .
It 's not right for it to end like this .
If we 're going to die , I want to be with you .
I want to be with you , and I 'm gonna come be with you .
Elliot , don 't .
[ Wind Whistling ]
[ Door Opens ]
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Wind Eases ]
[ Elliot ] The event must have ended before we went out there .
[ Children Shouting , Laughing ]
[ Alma ] I found the hair clip .
You don 't want to be late for the first day schools are open .
Oh , wait .
Um , I 'm just gonna put this right here .
Okay ?
- Are you okay ? - Yes , Aunt Alma .
I love you .
[ Voice Cracking ] I love you too .
All right . Pick you up after you 're done with school , okay ?
Good-bye .
As everyone knows by now , traces of the neurotoxin ...
have been found in some plants and trees .
Now most environmentalists feel that this event ...
is like - - like the red tide in the ocean ...
but instead of algae killing fish , this happened on land .
Plants and trees just can 't pick up and move ...
when they feel threatened , like other species .
They have only one option : to rapidly evolve their chemistry .
Well . Uh , Kay from Mississippi ...
wants to know why it started so suddenly - - on a Tuesday at 8 : 33 - -
and then ended so suddenly at 9 : 27 the next morning .
Well , Kay , to be perfectly honest ...
um , this was an act of nature ...
and we 'll never fully understand it .
And , Doctor , there 's been a lot of speculation ...
as to why this happened in the Northeast only .
How do you explain that ?
I believe - - All right ? And this is just my opinion .
That this was a prelude - -
A warning , like - - like - - like the first spot of a rash .
We have become a threat to this planet .
I don 't - - I don 't think anybody will argue that . And this is a warning .
A warning ? See , I think the skeptics would believe that ...
if it had occurred anywhere else .
That 's why most people believe it was the government .
If it had happened in one other place , anywhere else ...
we could all believe what you 're saying .
[ Exhales ]
- [ Chattering ] - [ Dog Barking ]
[ Speaking French ] I should drop my bicycle off at the apartment before I go to work .
[ French ] Can you make Nadia 's party tonight ?
I should drop my bicycle off at the apartment before I go to work .
[ Woman Screams ]
[ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ] That frightened me .
That frightened me .
I should drop my bicycle off
What ?
[ Wind Whistling ]
My God ...
My bicycle .